我是奧利弗•奎恩
My name is oliver queen.
五年裡  我被困在地獄一般的小島上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回來只有一個目標
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
To save my city.
但要達到目標
But to do so,
我不能像過去一樣成為兇手
I can't be the killer I once was.
為了紀念我的朋友
To honor my friend's memory,
我只能偽裝成另一個人
I must be someone else.
成為另一種存在
I must be something else.
《綠箭俠》前情回顧
Previously on "Arrow"...
布拉德打敗了我們所有重點培養的候選人
Blood's trounced every potential candidate we've focus-tested.
你想讓我去對抗塞巴斯蒂安•布拉德
You want me to run against Sebastian Blood?
拉斯•厄爾•高福的孩子正等著你回去
The child of Ra's Al Ghul awaits your return.
告訴拉爾斯•艾爾•古爾別惹我家人
Tell Ra's Al Ghul that my family is off limits!
-你應該回家了  -我不能
- You've got to come back home. - I can't!
如果她們知道我還活著  勞蕾爾和媽媽
If they knew I was alive, Laurel and mom,
她們會一直找我
they would never stop looking for me,
這會令她們都喪命
and that could get them both killed.
西婭•奎恩  告訴我夠了就是夠了
Thea Queen, telling me enough is enough.
現在有錢了
Now, that is rich.
莎拉
Sara?
歡迎來到星城國際機場
Welcome to Starling City International Airport.
請準備好您的護照
Please have your passports ready,
並填寫報關單
and your customs forms filled out.
所有離港航班的乘客
All passengers with departing flights
需要出示身份證明
will need to show appropriate identification
和紙質報關單
and declaration papers.
國際旅客需要持有護照
International passengers are required to have a passport
及登機牌
and an airline boarding pass to travel.
公務還是私事  蘭可小姐
Business or personal, Miss Raatko?
私事
Personal.
所有乘客需要
All passengers are required
自行在國際抵達及安檢處的
to pick up their luggage in the baggage claim area
行李認領區領取行李
of the international arrivals and safety.
超能力聯合調查組  安全警報
我的電腦死機了
My computer's froze.
你能稍等一下嗎  我馬上就回來
Can you hold on a sec? I'll be right back.
趴在地上  趴下  趴下
Down on the ground, down, down!
雙手舉過頭頂
Put your hands on your head!
聽到沒有  雙手舉過頭頂
I said, hands on your head.
女士  我會開槍的
Lady. I will shoot you.
綠   箭   俠
第二季第十三集
一場成功的市長競選的根本不在於民意調查
A successful mayoral campaign isn't about polling,
也並不在於籌得的資金量或者熱點問題
it isn't about fundraising or hot button issues.
而在於和民眾的聯繫
It's about connecting with people.
那就是明天在我們宣佈之後  莫伊拉
That's why right after we announce tomorrow, Moira,
我要讓你盡可能多地走到鏡頭面前的原因
I want to get you in front of as many cameras as possible.
早間秀  脫口秀
Morning shows, talk shows--
馬克  我想幫助重建這座城市
Mark, I want to help rebuild the city,
而不是迎合它
not pander to it.
那不是迎合  母親  那是競選宣傳
It's not pandering, mom. It's campaigning.
讓人們瞭解真實的莫伊拉•奎恩
Let the people get to know the real Moira Queen,
他們會愛上你的
and they are going to fall in love with you.
經驗之談
Speaking from experience,
這個人知道他在說什麼  莫伊拉
this man knows what he's talking about, Moira.
斯蒂爾先生
Mr. Steel?
我能和你說點事嗎
May I talk to you about something?
我不再是你的上司了  費利西蒂
I'm no longer your boss, Felicity.
所以從現在起叫我沃爾特就好
So let's make it Walter from now on.
好吧  沃爾特
Ok. Walter.
是有關暴風雨公司的事
It's about Tempest.
你去年讓我調查的奎恩女士的
Mrs. Queen's super sketchy offshore LLC
超級神秘的境外有限公司
you asked me to look into last year.
我記得
I remember.
是的
That's right.
事情是這樣的
So, the thing is,
我留下了一個嵌入式帳戶警告
I left an embedded account alert on it
這樣我們就能知道有誰再次嘗試接入它
so we'd know if anyone ever accessed it again.
幾天前  有一筆從暴風雨公司匯到
A few days ago, there was a wire transfer made
星城國家銀行的一個帳號的電子轉帳
from Tempest to a numbered account at Starling National Bank.
也許競選活動的會計師把它關閉了
Probably the campaign accountant shutting it down.
也許有其他原因
Or it could be something else.
那也許是奎恩女士用來做很糟糕的事的錢
That is the money Mrs. Queen used to do some really bad things.
我是指  你們倆離婚是有很好的理由的
I mean, you guys did get divorced for pretty good reasons.
當然那和我無關
Which is not my business.
我會盡快和莫伊拉談談的
I'll talk to Moira first thing.
謝謝你告知我
And thank you for bringing it to my attention.
當然
Of course.
接下來
Well...
我們要開啟一場競選活動了
we're starting a campaign.
-奧利弗  能和你說幾句嗎  -好的
- Oliver, can I have a word? - Yes.
我知道你和他是朋友
I know that you and he are friends,
但是你需要停止支援塞巴斯蒂安•布拉德
but you'll need to end your support for Sebastian Blood.
我會和塞巴斯蒂安說的
I will speak to Sebastian.
好的
Good.
蘭斯警探來電
喂
Hello?
我這就過去
I'll be right there.
奧利弗
Oliver.
蘭斯女士
Mrs. Lance.
我一聽到就馬上趕回來了
I came back as soon as I heard.
謝謝你能來
Thanks for coming.
你感覺如何
How you feeling?
我好多了
I've been better.
不用擔心  寶貝
Don't worry, baby.
我們會提供你所需的一切幫助
We're going to get you all the help you need.
星城外面有一家很好的康復中心
There's a great rehab outside of Starling,
他們給你準備了一個床位
they got a bed waiting for you--
父親  我告訴過你  我沒有吸毒過量
Dad, I already told you. I didn't OD.
我昨晚沒吃任何藥片
I didn't take any pills last night.
我發誓
I swear.
勞蕾爾
Laurel...
醫生想要檢查你的眼睛
The doctor wants to check your eye.
她的眼睛怎麼了
What happened to her eye?
結膜下輕微出血
Minor subconjunctival hemorrhaging.
可能是她昏迷後頭部撞擊造成的
Probably from hitting her head when she lost consciousness.
檢查完之後  她就可以出院了
After the exam, you can discharg her.
好起來  好嗎
You feel better, OK?
謝謝
Thank you.
我們到外面去  走吧
We'll be outside. Let's go.
爸爸
Dad.
怎麼了  甜心
What is it, sweetheart?
在我昏倒之前...
Before I passed out...
發生了很奇怪的事
the strangest thing happened.
我看到了莎拉
I saw Sara.
我知道我出現了幻覺  可是我真的看到她了
I mean, I know I was hallucinating, but I saw her.
她就站在我身邊
She was standing right over me.
我這些年一直夢到她
I mean, I've dreamt about her over the years,
但從沒有這麼真實過
but this was so much more real.
很瘋狂  是吧
That's crazy, right?
是的  很瘋狂
Yeah, it's crazy.
她已經這麼練了一個小時了
She's been doing that for like an hour.
你去見勞蕾爾了
You saw Laurel.
她不會有事吧
Is she going to be OK?
你救了她的命
You saved her life.
謝謝你打電話給我
Hey, thanks for calling me.
我從來沒問過...
And I never did ask you--
你怎麼找到我的
how did you find me?
我不會再失去你了
I wasn't going to lose you again.
我該走了
I should get going.
就這樣了嗎
Hey, so that's it?
你回到市裡24小時
You're back in town for 24 hours,
然後又要走嗎
now you're just going to take off again?
刺客聯盟依舊在找我  奧利
The League of Assassins is still after me, Ollie,
待在市裡會讓我的家人陷入危險
and staying in town would put my whole family at risk.
我回來只是因為勞蕾爾有麻煩
I only came because Laurel's in trouble.
她現在依然有麻煩  莎拉
Well, she's still in trouble, Sara.
你的家人都需要你
Your entire family needs you.
我也需要你
So do I.
幫我個忙  從醫院調取一份
Do me a favor and dig up a copy
勞蕾爾的血液化驗報告
of Laurel's bloodwork from the hospital, please.
沒問題  我們要查什麼
Sure. What are we looking for?
我只是想確定些事情
I just want to make sure of something.
找你的
It's for you.
你好  探長
Hello, detective.
讓我女兒接電話
Put my daughter on.
我知道她在
I know she's there.
六年前
希爾頓  告訴警督我給罪犯念他的權力時
Hilton, tell the lieutenant that the perp
他就基本已經要請律師了
was practically lawyering up when I read him his miranda.
如果我們不控制住局勢
If we don't get on top of this situation,
警督可不會開心...
the lieutenant is not going to be happy--
真香啊  爸爸
Oh, it smells amazing, dad.
是啊
Ahh, yeah.
-給  嘗嘗這個  -好的
- Here, try one of these. - OK.
-太棒了  -不  我在和勞蕾爾說話
- Beautiful. - No, I'm talking to Laurel.
昆汀  掛了電話  多陪陪你的家人
Quentin, hang up the phone. Spend time with your family!
我的家人  你聽到了吧
Oh, my family. You heard that,
我要掛了  再見  夥計
I got to go. Bye, buddy.
抱歉  女士們  兇手雇了個卑鄙的律師
Sorry, ladies. Our do-er hired some dirtbag lawyer, and--
這是女兒剛剛申請法學院的父親說的話嗎
Says the dad whose daughter just applied to law school.
你可不會變成
That is not the kind of
這樣的律師  年輕女士
lawyer that you're going to be, young lady,
你會變成一個法官
because you, you're going to be a judge
或者教授  就像你媽媽一樣
or you're going to be a professor, just like your mother.
是啊  來學術界混吧  樂趣無窮
Yeah, come over to academia. The fun never ends.
晚飯就要好了
Dinner is at a crucial point.
-你好啊  -莎拉小熊
- Hi! - Sar-bear!
你好啊
Hi.
-莎拉  真是意外啊  -你好啊  媽媽
- Sara, what a surprise. - Hi, mom.
別告訴我你被學校開除了
Please don't tell me you got kicked out of college.
謝謝你的信任
Oh, well, thank you for the vote of confidence.
我週末休假三天
I had a three day weekend,
所以我想回來  給大家一個驚喜
so I figured I'd drive down and surprise everybody.
你剛好趕上吃飯  過來
Well, you're just in time to eat. Come here.
自己拿個盤子  來吧
Get yourself another plate. Come on.
開飯了
Here you go.
奧利弗  你到了嗎
是的
你好  爸爸
Hi, dad.
過來
Come here.
我只能待幾分鐘
I only have a minute.
我只要喝杯茶的時間
Well, a cup of tea is all I ask.
坐下
Sit down.
寶貝
Oh, baby.
我想死你了
I have missed you so much.
勞蕾爾怎麼樣了
How's Laurel?
她看見你了
She saw you.
在她昏倒之前
Right before she passed out.
她覺得是...我也不知道是什麼...
She thought it was, I don't know what.
幻覺
a hallucination.
很好
Well, good.
不  寶貝  你不明白  看見你她很開心
No, baby, you don't understand. Seeing you, it made her happy.
爸爸  聯盟他們還在追殺我
Dad...the league, they're still hunting me.
所以呢  你就打算每次
So what, you're just going
我們有人有危險  你就回來嗎
to pop back every time one of us is in trouble?
我們不能這麼活著  莎拉  你也不能
We can't live like this, Sara, and you can't.
是時候我們一起面對了
It's time we started facing things together.
你的歡迎不是很熱情啊
I've had better greetings.
抱歉  我只是...我不知道
I'm sorry, I did-- I just--I didn't know
你會怎麼做
what you were going to do.
說實話  我也不知道
To be honest, neither did I.
我們得談談
We should talk.
當然
Of course.
需要你男朋友的允許嗎
Do we need permission from your boyfriend?
我是妮莎
I am Nyssa.
拉斯•厄爾•高福的女兒
Daughter of Ra's Al Ghul.
惡魔的後裔
Heir to the demon.
你來這兒幹什麼
What are you doing here?
莎拉對刺客聯盟宣誓了忠誠
Sara swore her allegiance to the League of Assassins.
她該回家了
It's time for her to return home.
這是絕對不會發生的事情
That...is not going to happen.
妮莎
Nyssa
求你了  能讓我們單獨談談嗎
Please, would you give us a moment?
慢慢談
Take your time.
告別本來就不是易事
Good-byes are never easy.
這就是為什麼你不辭而別了嗎
Is that why I didn't get one?
我可以解釋
I can explain.
不必解釋
You don't have to.
但是你不能離開
But you're not leaving.
我不信任她
I don't trust her.
那就信任我
Then trust me.
奎恩女士
Mrs. Queen?
有一位斯莫克小姐想要見您
A Miss Smoak is here to see you.
誰
Who?
是我
Uh, me.
如果你來找奧利弗的話  他不在這
If you're looking for Oliver, he's not here.
我知道  我是來見你的
I know. I'm here to see you.
是嗎  為了什麼
Really? What about?
暴風雨公司
Tempest.
我標記了你交易的一大筆電子轉帳
I flagged a large wire transfer you made.
當我跟沃爾特說起這個的時候
When I mentioned it to Walter,
他說他會跟你談談
he said he would talk to you about it.
我一看就知道他是不會跟你說的
I could tell in his face he wouldn't.
英國人不太擅長撒謊
British people are really bad liars.
沒錯
Yes, they are.
所以我自己查下去了
So I looked into it myself,
因為  說實話
Because--full disclosure--
我不相信你
I--I don't trust you.
你給一個叫吉爾醫生的人一大筆錢
You paid a substantial sum of money to a Dr. Gill.
他是接生西婭的醫生
He was the doctor who delivered Thea,
這對我來說完全不符合情理  所以在我想過
which didn't make any sense to me. So I went through
十幾個不同的推測後  我想起來
like a dozen different theories until I remembered...
你在審訊時做的證詞
your testimony. At trial.
你和馬爾科姆•梅林有過外遇
You had an affair with Malcolm Merlyn
就在西婭出生的前一年
one year before Thea was born.
梅林才是西婭的親生父親
Merlyn is Thea's father.
這會我知道為什麼沃爾特和奧利弗對你的能力
I can see why Walter and Oliver have such a high appraisal
有如此高的評價了
of your capabilities.
所以
So.
你要利用這條消息去幹什麼
What are you going to do with this information?
費利西蒂
Felicity.
我不知道
I don't know.
跟你在客廳對峙
Confronting you in your living room
和我的計劃大相徑庭
was as far as my plan went.
我認為你應該親口告訴奧利弗
I thought you deserved the chance to tell oliver yourself.
他應該從你口裡聽到這個消息
He should hear it from you.
我是不會告訴我兒子任何事情的
I'm not going to tell my son anything.
你也不會
And neither are you.
如果你不能為了奧利弗保守秘密
If you won't keep my secret for Oliver's sake,
你應該為了自己保守秘密
You should keep it for your own.
我看到你看他的眼神了
I see the way you look at him.
如果你告訴了他
If you tell him this,
你會讓他的世界崩塌
You will rip his world apart.
他心裡的一部分會一直責怪於你
And a part of him will always blame you.
他一定會恨我的
Oh, he'll hate me, for sure.
但是他也會恨你
But he will hate you, too.
我們都必須要保守秘密  斯莫克小姐
We all have to keep secrets, Miss Smoak.
你看起來變樣了
You look different.
我還是我
I'm still me.
我認識的那個莎拉是不會背叛我們
The Sara I know wouldn't have betrayed us
然後在夜幕的掩護下從南達爾巴特逃走
and fled Nanda Parbat under the cover of darkness.
我沒有選擇  那場地震
I didn't have a choice. The earthquake--
我必須要見到我的家人  確保他們的安全
I needed to see my family, make sure they were safe.
他們是安全的
And so they are.
回家吧
Come home.
我不能
I can't.
聽著  我不能回去  妮莎
Look, I can't go back, Nyssa.
我的靈魂已經殘缺不全了
I don't have much of a soul left in me,
但是不管還剩多少  它都經不起殺戮生活了
but what there is, it can't take the killing anymore.
你宣過誓的
You swore an oath.
我父親送我來就是為了確保你還在履行著
My father sent me here to make sure you honor it.
不成功便成仁
One way or another.
我們彼此都清楚你來的真正原因
We both know the real reason why you came here.
當我找到你的時候
When I found you,
你都快餓死了
you were starving,
而且孤單一人  只是在那兒等死
and alone, simply waiting to die.
聯盟接納了你
The League took you in...
照顧你恢復了健康
nursed you back to health.
你現在之所以活著都是因為我
The only reason you're alive today is because of me.
我跟你在一起不是因為你救了我
Hey, I wasn't with you because you saved me.
我跟你在一起是因為我愛你
I was with you because I loved you.
但現在不愛了
But not anymore.
拉斯聽你的話  你可以請求他放了我
Ra's listens to you. And you can ask him to release me.
我父親從未放過聯盟裡的任何人
My father has never released anyone from the League.
他放了馬爾科姆•梅林
He released Malcolm Merlyn.
一個令他和這個城市的人民都深深後悔的舉動
An action he and the citizens of this city dearly regret.
做你該做的
Do what you have to.
已經過去兩小時了
It's been two hours,
她現在應該回來找我了
And she should have gotten back in touch with me by now.
費利西蒂
Felicity.
-費利西蒂  -怎麼了
- Felicity! - What?!
對不起  怎麼了
Sorry. What?
你還好嗎
Are you OK?
我挺好的
Uh, yeah, I'm fine.
我只是在  想事情
It's just... things in here.
聯盟就沒有打算要放我走
The League is never going to let me go.
至少我在地球那邊
At least if I'm halfway around the world,
我還能保護我家人的安全
then I can keep my family safe.
我可不確定
I wouldn't be so sure about that.
剛拿到勞蕾爾的血液檢查結果
Just got a copy of Laurel's bloodwork.
她的毒品測試結果呈陰性反應
She tested negative for drugs.
那她為什麼暈倒了
Well, then why did she collapse?
因為他們在她血液裡發現了蛇毒的痕跡
Because they found traces of snake venom in her blood.
提煉於西藏蝮蛇
From a Tibetan pit viper.
等等  所以勞蕾爾沒有過量用藥
Wait. So Laurel didn't OD?
她是被人下毒的
She was poisoned.
妮莎幹的
She was poisoned by Nyssa,
為了讓你回來
who did it to draw you back here.
而且成功了
And it worked.
我的家人很危險
My family's in danger.
-跟誰發短信呢  -沒誰
- Who are you texting? - No one.
是不是在學校有喜歡的男孩了
Did you meet a boy at school?
少來了  學校的男生多無聊
Cut it out. Boys at school are lame.
你和奧利弗怎麼樣了
Hey, how's everything with you and Oliver?
很好
Great.
我們在考慮同居了
We decided to start looking at apartments together.
我知道發展地快了點  但是
I know it's a big step, but...
我們準備好了  打算同居一年後訂婚
We're ready. I think we'll live together for a year,
再一年就
engaged for another, and then...
成為勞蕾爾•奎恩夫人
Mrs. Laurel queen.
也許吧
Maybe one day.
但前提是他也想定下來
This is kind of assuming that he's ever ready to settle down.
你什麼意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我們都知道他睡過的女人一大把
Well, we both know at least ten girls that he's slept with.
你就不能為我高興一下嗎
Can't you just be happy for me?
要是你遇到了一個
I mean, if you met some amazing guy
你願意共度餘生的真愛
who wanted to spend the rest of his life with you,
我一定會支持你  為你高興
I would be so supportive, and so happy for you --
勞蕾爾  我沒想惹你
Ok, Laurel, I wasn't trying to be a bitch.
你總這麼說
The title of your autobiography.
我去睡了
I'm going to get some sleep.
碼頭見
不
No!
不要
星城醫院  急診樓
爸  都是我的錯  對不起
Dad, it's my fault, I'm so sorry.
你加入的刺客聯盟綁架了你媽媽
The Assassins Group that you're a part of, they took your mother.
不是
Not exactly.
那是誰
Well, what exactly?
一個女人
A woman.
她叫妮莎  聯盟裡一個重要人物
Nyssa. She's a powerful figure in the league.
是她給勞蕾爾下的毒  綁架了媽媽
And she poisoned laurel. She took mom.
為了逼你回聯盟
To get you to come back to the League?
為了讓我回她身邊
To get me to come back to her.
妮莎  別這麼做
Nyssa, don't do this.
我警告過你  但你不聽
I tried to warn you, but you wouldn't listen.
我覺的只有讓你
I thought it would be
切身體會到突然失去一個深愛的人的感覺
instructive for you to know what it feels like
你才能明白我的感受
to suddenly lose someone you love.
讓他們毫無徵兆的從你的生活裡消失
To have them ripped from your life without warning.
不要傷害我媽媽
You do not want to hurt my mother.
對  我確實不想
You're right. I don't.
你有一天時間考慮  塔爾•莎菲爾
You have one day, Ta-er Sah-fer.
選擇權在你
Make the right choice.
還有24小時
We have 24 hours.
探長  我們會找到她的
Detective... we'll find her.
勞蕾爾在裡面還昏迷著  我得回去了
Ok, Laurel's inside, she's losing her mind, I got to go.
保持聯繫
Keep me updated.
拜託
Oh, come on!
打的跟業餘的一個水準
You ought to buy a ticket if you're going to play like that!
孩子  房子找到了嗎
Hey, kiddo. How's the apartment hunt going?
八字沒一撇呢  我想找個很完美的房子
Terribly. I really wanted to find the perfect place
在奧利出海回來後給他個驚喜
to show Ollie when he gets back from his boat trip.
我都來不及看上一眼
Everything good was already taken
好房子就沒了
by the time I walked in the door.
這是上帝在告訴你
Maybe it's a sign that you're not supposed to move in
你不該隨便和男友同居
with the frat boy that you call a boyfriend.
你和我媽在我這麼大的時候
You and mom were my age
早都在春日街同居了吧
when you moved into that place on Spring Street.
你們那時還沒訂婚呢
You weren't even engaged yet.
那是因為你母親總
Well, that's 'cause your mother
拒絕我的求婚
kept turning down all my proposals.
真的假的
She did?
她就是那樣  自由第一  不願束縛
Oh, you know your mother, free spirit and all.
說什麼愛情為什麼需要戒指證明
Why do we need rings when we have love?
拖了一年才答應我的求婚
You know I spent a year with that
戒指都快把我的口袋磨穿了
damn ring burning a hole in my pocket?
收到求救信號很久了
A mayday transmission was heard,
但目前為止  仍沒有金牌奎恩號的蹤跡
but so far there has been no trace of the "Queen's Gambit".
金牌奎恩號失蹤
六時至今求救信號也沒再出現
And that's not has been heard from six.
失蹤人員有本地居民
Among those missing are local residents
無人生還
羅伯特•奎恩和奧利弗•奎恩
Robert and Oliver queen.
有黛娜的蹤跡嗎
Do we have a lead on dinah?
我們化驗了妮莎給勞蕾爾下的毒
We researched the poison Nyssa used on Laurel.
很幸運  那是西藏蝮蛇毒
Luckily for us, Tibetan pit viper venom
毒性很難轉移
is surprisingly difficult to transport.
在離開毒牙後毒性會大大降低
It starts losing its potency the moment it leaves the fangs.
沒想到我會說出這種詭異的句子
Yet another sentence I never thought I'd actually say out loud.
所以是現買的
So it was bought locally?
不是買的  是偷的
Not bought. Stolen.
-從哪裡偷  -動物園
- From where? - The zoo.
本地動物園遭竊  沒有物品遺失
A local break-in. The perps didn't steal anything,
員警定案為
So the cops chalked it
孩子的惡作劇
up to a bunch of kids looking for a thrill.
我調出了當晚公園內部的監控錄影
I pulled up the zoo CCTV footage from the night of the break-in.
拍到了一個車牌
I caught a plate.
車是租來的
The car's a rental.
是貧民區的車
Address is in the Glades.
莎拉  給你父親打電話
Sara. Call your father.
塞巴斯蒂安  我很抱歉
Sebastian, I am so sorry.
我總是放你鴿子
I have a bad habit of standing you up.
我知道你一直都很支持我的競選
Look, I know you have to pull your support for my campaign.
親情比政治更重要
Blood is thicker than politics.
可以理解
And it should be.
謝謝你能理解我
Well, thank you for understanding,
我希望這不會影響到我們的友誼
And I really hope that this doesn't affect our friendship.
-它對我來說很重要  -對我也是
- It's important to me. - And to me.
有什麼能為你效勞的嗎  議員先生
Can I help you, Alderman?
我只是來見您兒子的
Oh, I had a meeting with your son.
你應該知道我們要談什麼吧
I'm sure you can guess the topic.
我希望我與你競爭市長的決定
I hope my decision to run against you for mayor
不會影響你們之間的關係
doesn't affect your relationship.
出於對我與您兒子關係的尊重
Out of respect for that relationship,
我能給你提些建議嗎
can I offer some advice?
-請講  -退出
- Please. - Get out.
現在
Now.
我還沒宣佈要競選市長
The fact that you are advising me to get out
你就要我退出
before I even announce my candidacy
這說明我威脅到了你
suggests that you're threatened.
我很擔心會毀了朋友的母親
I'm apprehensive about destroying my friend's mother.
-我可以照顧好自己  -真的嗎
- I can take care of myself. - Really?
在受審時  你將自己扮演成
During your trial, you portrayed yourself
一個被馬爾科姆•梅林玩弄於股掌的弱者
as a fragile creature living under Malcolm Merlyn's thumb.
你到底要扮演哪種角色
So which is it?
是一個能領導這座城市的女強人
The woman strong enough to lead this city,
還是一個意志薄弱無法拯救它的可憐蟲
or the one too weak willed to save it?
是一個不應該被低估的人
The one who should not be underestimated.
來這兒以後具體要做什麼
So what exactly is the plan here?
等待  綠箭俠會帶他來見我們
We wait. The Arrow will lead him right to us.
你從來沒告訴過我
You know, you never did tell me
你最初是怎麼加入綠箭俠的
how you joined up with the Arrow in the first place.
你們在哪兒遇見的
Where did you two even meet?
治安維持者俱樂部
Vigilante Club.
還是原來的樣子
Same old Sara.
不過  也不完全一樣了
Well, not exactly the same.
我愛她  爸爸
I loved her, Dad.
你難過嗎
Are you upset?
說實話  莎拉
Honestly, Sara,
想到過去6年
to think what you've been through
你經歷過的那些
these past six years?
痛苦  孤獨
The pain, the loneliness...
我很高興聽到有人照顧你
I'm just happy to hear you had someone that cared for you.
什麼情況  他們在刺客學校裡
What's the matter, they didn't teach you
沒教過你右勾拳嗎
about right crosses in assassin school?
-妮莎在哪  -我老婆在哪
- Where is Nyssa?! - Tell me where my wife is!
-他在說什麼鬼話  -他在祈禱
- What the hell is he saying? - He's praying.
不  你不能...你不能...
No, don't you... don't you
王八蛋
Son of a bitch!
結束了  探長
It's over, detective.
他死了
He's gone.
莎拉那邊怎麼樣
How's Sara holding up?
不順利  現在我需要你
Not well. And I need you
去查出妮莎的行蹤
to pick up the trail on Nyssa,
因為蘭斯夫人就快沒有時間了
because Mrs. Lance is running out of time.
我馬上去
I'm on it.
奧利弗
Oh, Oliver.
-費利西蒂  -你好
- Felicity. - Hi, hi.
自從我舉行婚禮那天後
Well, I haven't been this nervous
還沒這麼緊張過
since my wedding day.
-他們也是  -莫伊拉  時間到了
- Both of them. - Moira, it's time.
奧利弗  你準備好介紹你母親了嗎
Oliver, are you ready to introduce your mother?
非常榮幸
With pride.
費利西蒂
Felicity?
Felicity.
你怎麼了
What is going on with you?
-別說...  -沒事
- And don't say... - Nothing.
別說"沒事"
Don't say "nothing."
說實話  好嗎
The truth, please.
你可能注意到了我話很多
Might have noticed that I talk a lot.
我注意到了
It has not escaped my attention.
你可能也發現了我很少提起
You might have also noticed that I don't talk a lot
-我的家人  -我發現了
- about my family. - I have noticed that.
我媽媽...
My mother is...
她...
She's...
我媽媽是我媽媽
She's my mother.
可是
And...
我不知道我父親是誰
I don't really know what my father is,
因為他拋棄了我們
'cause he abandoned us.
我幾乎不記得他
I barely remember him.
但我確實記得...
But I do remember...
他離開時我有多傷心
how much it hurt when he left.
而一想到
And just the thought of
再一次失去對我來說重要的人
losing someone that important to me again...
你不會失去我的
You're not going to lose me.
無論是什麼讓你煩惱...
Whatever it is that's bothering you...
是你家人的事嗎
Is it about your family?
不
No.
是你家人的事
It's about yours.
時間到了
Time's up.
你做好決定了嗎
Have you made your decision?
莎拉•蘭斯  1987-2007  摯愛的女兒和妹妹
放了我媽媽
Let my mother go.
我會和你回南達爾巴特
And I will return with you to Nanda Parbat.
莎拉  你做了正確的選擇
You're doing the right thing, Sara.
對我們來說都是
For both of us.
甜心  給你
Here you go, sweetie.
你的甘菊精油  是你喜歡的那種
Your chamomile, like you like.
你還要別的什麼嗎  我拿給你
Is there anything else I can get you?
我媽媽
My mother.
勞蕾爾  有些事我得告訴你
Laurel, there's something I got to tell you.
是有關於你妹妹的
It's about your sister.
關於她的什麼事
What about her?
你好
Hello?
爸爸  我找到媽媽了
Dad, I found mom.
30分鐘後來矮船塢見我
Meet me at the Lower Boat Yards in 30 minutes,
一個人來
and come alone.
不要告訴綠箭俠
Don't tell the Arrow.
知道了
Copy that.
我得走了
I got to go.
莎拉怎麼了  爸爸
What about Sara, Dad?
我稍後會向你解釋一切的  好嗎
I'll explain everything later, all right?
你老實待著
Just sit tight.
我很有信心這麼說
I say this with confidence.
因為我所認識的莫伊拉•奎恩
Because the Moira Queen that I know is more
不僅是一名成功的總裁和慈善家
than a successful CEO and philanthropist.
她更是一名疼愛子女  把自己的一生
She is a loving mother who has devoted her life
都奉獻給了自己的兩個孩子的母親
to raising two wonderful children.
為了讓大家瞭解她是多麼特別
Just to tell you how special she is,
我想有請她的兒子
I'd like to welcome her son.
奎恩聯合企業總裁  奧利弗•奎恩先生
CEO of Queen Consolidated, Mr. Oliver Queen.
奎恩競選市長
謝謝
Thank you.
我今天想要簡單說一說
Well, I'm here today to say a few words...
莫伊拉•奎恩
about Moira Queen.
我想你們很多人都認為自己瞭解她
I bet many of you think that you know her,
因為你們
because you...
在報紙上讀過她的新聞
read about her in the press,
或者在電視上見過她
or you saw her on TV.
但是我敢說
But I can promise you...
你們並不瞭解我的母親
you don't know my mother.
不像我這麼瞭解她
You don't know her like I do.
而且你們不知道她的能力
And you don't know what she's capable of...
凡是涉及到幫助
when it comes to helping
星城人民的事情
the people of Starling City.
女士們先生們
Ladies and gentlemen...
我的母親
my mother,
莫伊拉•奎恩
Moira Queen.
我知道
I know.
謝謝大家
Thank you!
謝謝你  星城
Thank you, Starling City.
莎拉
Sara!
蛇毒  不見了
The snake venom, it's gone.
她發現了妮莎
She found Nyssa.
她想要毒死她嗎
And she's going to poison her?
我們得趕緊阻止她
We need to stop her before she does.
啟動她的追蹤器
Activate her tracer.
你給她安了追蹤器
You put a tracer on her?
她經常一聲不響就離開我
She has a bad habit of disappearing on me.
奧利弗  不是我冷血  但是我們
Oliver, I hate to sound cold, but why do we care
為什麼要阻止莎拉殺壞人
if Sara kills some bad ass
那個殺手想要殺死她和她家人啊
assassin that wants to get her and her family?
狄格爾  因為如果我所聽說過的
Because, Diggle, if half of the stories
有關拉斯•厄爾•高福的事有一半是真的
that I have heard about Ra's Al Ghul are true,
那麼要是莎拉殺了他的女兒
if Sara kills his daughter...
我們都要付出代價
we will all pay.
他們來找你了
They're coming for you now.
戴娜  快離開她  離開她
Dinah! Move away from her! Move away!
沒事了  沒事了
It's all right, it's all right.
怎麼回事
What's happening?
莎拉
Sara...
是我  媽媽
It's me, mom.
是我
It's me.
我的寶貝
Oh, my baby!
My baby!
我的寶貝
Oh, my baby!
我很愛你  媽媽
I love you so much, mom.
但我要走了
I have to go.
什麼  你要幹什麼
What? What are you doing?
-爸  帶媽離開這裡  -什麼
- Dad, get mom out of here! - What?!
-我們得走了  -不
- We've got to go. - No!
不
No!
你服了毒藥
You took the poison.
不
No!
我不能再回頭了
I can't go back.
我不能再殺人了
I can't take the killing anymore.
到此為止吧
It needs to end.
莎拉  警員DC-52呼叫總部
Sara! Delta Charlie 52, to central,
船塢這裡需要支援
need back up at the lower boat yards.
快派救護車和醫療人員來
Ambulance, paramedics...
如果你這麼想跟家人在一起
If you want to be with your family so badly,
他們很快就能跟你長眠地下了
they can join you in eternity.
莎拉
Sara!
離我女兒遠點
You get the hell away from my daughter.
生或死
Live or die.
由你決定
It's up to you.
莎拉  我還能救活她
Sara. I can still save her.
還是擔心一下你怎麼救你自己吧
Worry more about saving yourself.
不要殺她
Don't kill her.
求你了
Please.
莎拉
Sara...
Sara!
莎拉  堅持住
Sara, hold on.
別睡  拜託
Stay with me. Come on.
拜託  不要死
Come on, stay.
不要又離我而去
Not again.
不要再殺人了
No more killing.
妮莎
Nyssa.
求你了
Please.
塔爾•莎菲爾
Ta-er Sah-fer,
我以拉斯•厄爾•高福的名義
in the name of Ra's Al Ghul...
還你自由
I release you.
莎拉
Sara.
寶貝  你還好嗎
Sweetheart, are you all right?
謝天謝地你沒事
Thank God you're OK!
因為星城是我們自己的城市
Because Starling City is our city.
所以從今天開始  我們要把它奪回來
and starting today, we're going to take it back.
我知道我們得談談
I know we need to talk.
你需要聽我說
You need to listen.
這麼多年來
For the past year,
我一直支持你
I have stood by your side...
我為你抗爭努力過
And I have fought,
因為我想相信你不是別人口中的那個
because I wanted to believe that you weren't this...
魔鬼
monster.
我也需要相信我還有母親
And I needed to believe that I still had a mother.
你有母親  奧利弗
You do, Oliver--
奧利弗  我跟西婭說謊
Oliver, I only lied about Thea
是想保護她不受馬爾科姆的威脅
to protect her from Malcolm.
不  你說謊是因為你一向如此
No, you lied because that is what you do.
是因為你天性就是如此  媽
And that is who you are, mom.
騙子
Lies.
現在  你又把我培養成了騙子
And now you've made a liar out of me.
因為西婭永遠都不能知道梅林的事
Because Thea could never find out about Merlyn.
她也永遠不能知道我們之間的真相
And she could never know the truth about us.
就是從現在開始  我們再無瓜葛
Which is that as of right now, we have no relationship.
為了西婭  我會一直裝好樣子的
I will keep up appearances for Thea's sake.
對外我會支援你的競選
And publicly, I will support your campaign.
但是私底下
But privately...
我們之間再無關係
you and I are done.
奧利弗
Oliver...
Oliver.
奧利弗
Oliver!
我就知道你肯定還活著
I knew you were alive.
我能感覺得到
I just felt it in my balls.
我一直在找你  從未停止
I never stop looking for you.
我知道你現在滿腦子的疑問
I know you have a lot of questions.
沒有
Nope.
你怎麼會沒有疑問呢
How could you not have any questions?
因為我已經知道所有疑問的答案了
Because I already know all of the answers to them.
你怎麼還活著
How could you still be alive?
這期間你都去哪裡了
Where have you been all this time?
你為什麼不給我們打電話
Why didn't you call us.
所有問題的答案
And the answer to all of them...
都是因為你是莎拉
is because it's Sara.
-寶貝  別這樣  -爸  我發誓
- Baby, don't do this-- - Dad, I swear to God,
如果你再多說一個字
if you say one more word.
勞蕾爾  我知道你很生氣
Laurel, look, I know you're angry.
你生氣也是理所當然的
And you have every right to be.
但是求你不要怪爸爸
But please don't take this out on dad.
如果你想怪誰的話  就怪我吧
If you need someone to blame, blame me.
我確實怪你  莎拉
Oh, I do blame you, Sara.
我們生活中出現的所有不愉快
Every single thing that's gone wrong in our lives
都是你的錯
is your fault.
你跟我男朋友一起上了那艘破船
You got on that stupid boat with my boyfriend.
你沒打電話告訴我們你還活著
You didn't call us to tell us that you were still alive,
即使那樣可能拯救爸媽的婚姻
even though it probably would have saved mom and dad's marriage.
你還把什麼瘋子殺手帶進了星城
And you brought some crazy assassin into Starling City
差點害死了媽  還下毒害我
who nearly killed mom and who poisoned me.
是你
You.
是你搶走了我的人生
You stole my whole life away from me.
-你給我滾  -勞蕾爾
- Now get out. - Laurel...
滾出去
Get out.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我讓你滾
I said get out!
等等
Hold on.
請進
Please, come in.
奧利弗沒事吧
Tell me Oliver is OK!
一切都沒事對不對
Tell me everything's OK!
我也希望如此
I wish I could.
莫伊拉  很遺憾羅伯特和奧利弗
Moira, I'm so sorry about Robert.
發生了那樣的不測
About Oliver.
真的很遺憾
I really am.
我需要跟你們說件事
Yes, um, I need to tell you both something.
什麼事
What is it?
失蹤的不止是羅伯特和奧利弗
Robert and Oliver weren't the only ones lost.
除了船員之外
Along with the crew,
奧利弗最後時刻還邀請了一位朋友上船
a friend invited along by Oliver at the last minute.
-是湯米嗎  -不是
- Tommy. - No.
是...
It was...
是莎拉
It was Sara.
你們家的莎拉
Your Sara.
真的很遺憾  昆汀
I'm so sorry, Quentin.
船塢的主人看到她偷溜上船了
The dock master saw her sneak on board.
雖然莫伊拉•奎恩今天發表的演講令人印象深刻
With Moira Queen's impressive speech earlier today,
但是一些學者說她的競選之路
some pundits are suggesting her candidacy
莫伊拉•奎恩宣佈競選市長
可能走不了太遠
might not be so far-fetched.
雖然布拉德還未對奎恩夫人的聲明
And while Blood's campaign has yet to issue a public response
作出公開回應...
to Mrs. Queen's announcement...
我警告過你  不要低估莫伊拉•奎恩
I warned you not to underestimate Moira Queen.
你想讓我怎麼做
What do you want me to do?
謝謝大家
Thank you!
莫伊拉•奎恩宣佈競選市長
謝謝你  星城
Thank you, Starling City!
你什麼都不用做
Nothing.
一切由我來處理
I'll take care of it.
你哭過了
You've been crying.
是啊  知道自己還會哭真好
Yeah, I was happy to know I still could.
你沒事吧
Are you OK?
勞蕾爾看到我後沒你想像的那麼高興
Well, Laurel wasn't as thrilled to see me as you thought.
給她點時間
Give her time.
我已經給了她六年時間了
I gave her six years.
你朝那個假人身上發洩什麼呢
What exactly are you taking out on that dummy?
我母親...
My mother...
她不是我想像的那樣
She's not who I thought she was.
這應該不是什麼秘密了吧
I guess it's going around.
那現在怎麼辦
So what now?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我也是
I don't, either.
但我知道一件事
I know one thing.
什麼事
What's that?
我回家了
I'm home.